Earl Stanley and Charles H. Stewart Theater Collection MS173
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Earl Stanley and Charles H. Stewart Theater Collection
1890 -- 1970
1880 -- 1995
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Stewart, Earl Stanley
MS173
34.8 Linear Feet 26 boxes, 1 oversized folder
Arrangement
This collection is organized in two series: Earl Stanley Stewart theater collection and Charles H. Stewart theater collection.
Custodial History
The Charles H. Stewart collection was brought to DCA sometime in the early 2000s without documentation or a donor agreement. These materials were eventually moved to the DCA stacks in 2010, but remained uncataloged until the DCA collections survey in June 2016. The Earl Stanley Stewart collection was accessioned in 2014. A donor agreement covering the whole collection, Charles H. and Earl Stanley Stewart, was received on March 24, 2014. It can be found in the physical collection documentation folder for MS173.
Biographical / Historical
Earl Stanley Stewart (1907-1993) was born in 1907 to Charles H. and Mina W. Stewart. He worked for his father's theater backdrop company in Somerville for a number of years. He served in the military in World War II and married a British woman in 1946 before returning to the United States. Stewart was also an avid theater historian and collected materials related to the history of theater. He died in 1993 at the age of 86.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials related to the history of theater collected by Earl Stanley Stewart and his father, Charles H. Stewart. There is a particular emphasis on the theater scene in the greater Boston area in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Greater Boston arts; Theater--History--19th century.; Theater--History--20th century.; Theater--History--20th century--Periodicals.; Drama
- Earl Stanley Stewart theater collection, 1880 -- 1995; 1880 -- 1970; MS173.001; 19.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of materials related to the history of theater collected by Stanley Stewart. There is a particular emphasis on the theater scene in the greater Boston area in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries.
  Arrangement
  This series is loosely arranged by format.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Programs, 1880 -- 1900; MS173-001 (Box data_value_missing_e73f431bb4e1da6f2991e9c1bb09b3d2, Box 2)
  - News clippings, photographs, 1940 -- 1960; MS173-002 (Box data_value_missing_e73f431bb4e1da6f2991e9c1bb09b3d2, Box 4)
  - Scores. photos, supply catalogs, 1940 -- 1970; MS173-003 (Box data_value_missing_6364141555baaa321f5cf121b48a7299, Box 6)
  - Programs, scrapbook, production notes, 1890 -- 1970; MS173-004 (Box data_value_missing_6364141555baaa321f5cf121b48a7299, Box 8)
  - Production notes, 1900 -- 1980; MS173-005 (Box data_value_missing_6364141555baaa321f5cf121b48a7299, Box 10)
  - Plays, playbills, 1900 -- 1970; MS173-006 (Box data_value_missing_9992be92d1e6e8284fba0c70c970b4b9, Box 12)
  - Old scrapbooks, 1880 -- 1970; MS173-007 (Box data_value_missing_1cc2ea16b43598d5c6ae380dac7aee20, Box 14)
  - Scripts, 1900 -- 1960; MS173-008 (Box data_value_missing_44f495ac711fe1f777382e5f1c41fd86, Box 16)
  - Folders, scrapbooks, pubs, 1920 -- 1960; MS173-009 (Box data_value_missing_e66e9445fec96c412a36f50c5ad056ca, Box 18)
  - Folders, scripts, 1900 -- 1970; MS173-010 (Box data_value_missing_46b9e27bf9a23a824b077bd7cabebd84, Box 20)
  - Plays, 1930 -- 1960; MS173-011 (Box data_value_missing_46b9e27bf9a23a824b077bd7cabebd84, Box 22)
  - Scrapbooks, 1890 -- 1940; MS173-012 (Box data_value_missing_06f0e4f9492507ae717b8eaebb7f6bc6, Box 24)
  - Theatre management notebooks and plays, 1900 -- 1995; MS173-013 (Box data_value_missing_46b9e27bf9a23a824b077bd7cabebd84, Box 26)
  - Stage set design boards, MS173-014 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 3)
- Charles H. Stewart theater collection, 1895 -- 1995; MS173.002; 15.6 Linear Feet
  This series consists of materials related to the history of theater collected by Charles H. Stewart. The bulk of the materials are newspapers and publications that feature articles related to drama and theater.
  - Photographs and scrapbook pages, 1920 -- 1950; MS173-015 (Box data_value_missing_784a11fd1a53719b0bda2e4dce305cd7, Box 1)
  - Publications and newspaper clippings, 1950 -- 1980; MS173-016 (Box data_value_missing_784a11fd1a53719b0bda2e4dce305cd7, Box 3)
  - Publications and playbills, 1950 -- 1990; MS173-017 (Box data_value_missing_784a11fd1a53719b0bda2e4dce305cd7, Box 5)
  - Scrapbook and newspaper clippings, 1895 -- 1950; MS173-018 (Box data_value_missing_3d094ae9c758cb1e7ed5b8958ea82163, Box 7)
  - Theater books and related materials, 1930 -- 1985; MS173-019 (Box data_value_missing_3d094ae9c758cb1e7ed5b8958ea82163, Box 9)
  - Newspapers and drama materials, 1930 -- 1970; MS173-020 (Box data_value_missing_3d094ae9c758cb1e7ed5b8958ea82163, Box 11)
  - Newspapers and publications, 1970 -- 1990; MS173-021 (Box data_value_missing_33ef4764fc5ddea938b748af0bcdc40f, Box 13)
  - Newspapers and publications, 1980 -- 1995; MS173-022 (Box data_value_missing_33ef4764fc5ddea938b748af0bcdc40f, Box 15)
  - Newspaper clippings and publications, 1950 -- 1980; MS173-023 (Box data_value_missing_33ef4764fc5ddea938b748af0bcdc40f, Box 17)
  - Photographs, 1920 -- 1970; MS173-024 (Box data_value_missing_8adff19712bd95046cc4a6d9f21218a0, Box 19)
  - Theater books and related materials, 1980 -- 1995; MS173-025 (Box data_value_missing_72268c46ad67882e0bf2204ce272066f, Box 21)
  - Theater publications, 1940 -- 1980; MS173-026 (Box data_value_missing_72268c46ad67882e0bf2204ce272066f, Box 23)
  - Scrapbook pages and posters, 1920 -- 1950; MS173-027 (Box data_value_missing_0e7260952d94969f2de797ca88e807f8, Box 25)